http://www.stsci.edu/privacy

Skip to main content
Menu
Main Navigation
STScI Home
Who We AreSTScI Annual ReportsOur HistorySTScI TimelineMeet Our DirectorLeadershipWhat We DoHubble Space TelescopeAboutKey Science ThemesSolar SystemExoplanetsStars and Their EnvironmentsGalaxiesCosmologyHST ScorecardHistoryKey IndividualsSpace Telescope Users CommitteeMembershipCommittee ReportsPresentations and DocumentationHST Repair Contingency PlansProposingPhase ICall for ProposalsDirector's Discretionary Time SubmissionMid-Cycle Time SubmissionProposal Planning ToolboxExposure Time CalculatorOrbital Visibility and SchedulingPeer Review InformationPhase IIPhase II Proposal PreparationPhase II Proposal InstructionsVisit Size RecommendationsGuidelines and DocumentsApproved ProgramsJoint XMM-HST ProgramsObservingSchedulingActivating Your Target of OpportunityObserving StatusProgram InformationPost-ObservationData Analysis ToolboxReporting ProblemsRetrieving Data on MASTHubble Legacy ArchiveInstrumentationAdvanced Camera for SurveysInstrument DesignPerformanceAnneal DatesAnomalies and ArtifactsDragon's Breath and Edge GlowGuidestarsCTE InformationPost-SM4 Internal CTE for WFCPhotometric CTE CorrectionsPixel-Based CTE CorrectionsPrism / GrismWFC G800LHRC G800LHRC PR200LSBC PR110L and PR130LProposingACS ETCDither StrategiesACS-WFC-DITHER-LINEACS-WFC-DITHER-BOXACS-WFC-MOSAIC-LINEACS-WFC-MOSAIC-BOXACS-HRC-DITHER-LINEACS-HRC-DITHER-BOXACS-HRC-MOSAIC-LINEACS-HRC-MOSAIC-BOXACS-SBC-DITHER-LINEACS-SBC-DITHER-BOXACS-SBC-MOSAIC-LINEACS-SBC-MOSAIC-BOXData AnalysisAperture CorrectionsDistortionDQ Flag DefinitionsDrizzlePacPixel Area MapsSystem ThroughputsZeropointsPhotometric TransformationsCalibrationCalibration PlansReference FilesSoftware ToolsAnalysis ToolsCalibration ToolsDrizzlePacDocumentationInstrument Science Reports (ISRs)STScI Analysis Newsletter (STAN)Conference PostersShortcutsACS ISRsACS STANsACS Imaging ETCACS Spectroscopic ETCACS Ramp Filter ETCHST ProposingPhase I ProposalsPhase II ProposalHST Cycle 27 PrimerCosmic Origins SpectrographInstrument DesignPerformanceMonitoringSensitivitySpectral ResolutionProposingCOS2025 PoliciesObserving StrategiesWavelength ToolData Analysis & Software ToolsCalibrationAirglowCycle 28 Calibration PlanCycle 27 Calibration PlanCycle 26 Calibration PlanCycle 25 Calibration PlanCycle 24 Calibration PlanCycle 23 Calibration PlanCycle 22 Calibration PlanCycle 21 Calibration PlanCycle 20 Calibration PlanCycle 19 Calibration PlanCycle 18 Calibration PlanCycle 17 Calibration PlanDocumentationInstrument Science Reports (ISRs)STScI Analysis Newsletter (STAN)Conference PostersCalCOS Release NotesFine Guidance SensorsHistoryInstrument DesignPerformanceProposingData AnalysisSoftware ToolsDocumentationSpace Telescope Imaging SpectrographInstrument DesignAperturesDetectorsFiltersGratings / PrismSpectral Format PlotsPerformanceAnomaliesImage QualityMonitoringSensitivitySpectral ResolutionThroughputBackground NoiseProposingGO Wavecal Aperture SelectionObserving StrategiesTarget AcquisitionSpectroscopyImagingAvailable ModesHigh Contrast Coronagraphy at Small Inner Working Angles with BAR5STIS BAR5Data Analysis and Software ToolsPixel Based CTICalibrationDocumentationInstrument Science ReportsSTScI Analysis Newsletter (STAN)Wide Field Camera 3Instrument DesignPerformanceAnomaliesCTEGround TestingMonitoringComplete Anneal HistoryThroughputsProposingDithering StrategiesData AnalysisColor Conversion TableFull Well DepthGrism SpectroscopyIR FlatsIR PersistencePhotometric CalibrationUVIS Photometric CalibrationUVIS Photometric Zero PointsQuad Filter PhotometryUVIS Encircled EnergyIR Photometric CalibrationIR Encircled EnergyPixel Area MapsPSFPSF SearchRetrieving DataShould I Recalibrate?UVIS FlatsPost-ObservationCalibrationTV3 ResultsTV2 ResultsTV1 ResultsOld VersionsSoftware ToolsCrosstalkCTE ToolsExposure Time CalculatorsPipelineSPAR ToolDocumentationInstrument Science Reports (ISRs)STScI Analysis Newsletter (STAN)Grism ResourcesGrism Frequently Asked QuestionsWFC3 G141 CalibrationsWFC3 G280 CalibrationsWFC3 G102 CalibrationsWFC3 IR Grism Data Reduction CookbookIR Grism Master Sky ImagesConference PostersNewsFocus and PointingFocusSecondary Mirror MovesHST Focus ModelTiny Tim HST PSF ModelingPointingJitter File Format DefinitionDetermining an Observation’s OrientationFoV GeometryDocumentationLegacy InstrumentsNICMOSInstrument Science Reports (ISRs)WFPC2Instrument Science Reports (ISRs)Reference Data for Calibration and ToolsCalibration Reference Data System (CRDS)File and Table StructuresReference File Retrieval InstructionsLegacy Instrument Reference FilesSynphot Throughput TablesAstronomical CatalogsCALOBSCALSPECCastelli and Kurucz AtlasPickles AtlasPhoenix Models available in pysynphotBuser-Kurucz AtlasKurucz 1993 ModelsBruzual AtlasGunn-Stryker Atlas listBruzual-Persson-Gunn-Stryker Atlas listJacoby-Hunter-Christian AtlasThe Bruzual-Charlot AtlasThe Kinney-Calzetti Spectral AtlasThe AGN AtlasThe Galactic Emission Line Object AtlasNon-Stellar SpectraKinney ModelsBruzual and Charlot 2003Brown Dwarfs and Substellar ObjectsInterstellar Extinction CurvesThe TRDS Brown AtlasModewave DataDocumentationDocumentationHandbook ArchiveNews & EventsNewsArticlesEventsPressJames Webb Space TelescopeAboutHistoryHistorical Sensitivity EstimatesJWST Advisory Committee (JSTAC)FlyersWhite PapersDesign Reference Mission (DRM)Science Operations Design Reference Mission (SODRM)Solar System ProgramsExoplanet ProgramsGalactic ProgramsNearby Galaxies ProgramsDistant Galaxies and Cosmology ProgramsInstrumentation Calibration ProgramsObservation Calibration ProgramsStatistical SummaryScience ThemesNews & EventsNewsEventsArticlesInstrumentationScience InstrumentsImaging ModesSpectroscopic ModesScience PlanningCalls for Proposals and PolicyProposal Planning ToolboxExposure Time CalculatorPSF Simulation ToolTarget Visibility ToolsSimulated DataSensitivity and Saturation LimitsMIRISimMirageJISTProposal TrainingUser CommitteesJWST Users CommitteeJWST Science Working GroupObserving ProgramsProgram InformationApproved ERS ProgramsERS Program 1288ERS Program 1309ERS Program 1324ERS Program 1328ERS Program 1334ERS Program 1335ERS Program 1345ERS Program 1349ERS Program 1355ERS Program 1364ERS Program 1366ERS Program 1373ERS Program 1386Approved GTO ProgramsCalibration ProgramsData Analysis ToolboxScience PublicationsDocumentationNancy Grace Roman Space TelescopeAboutScience ThemesPartnersRoman Space Telescope Advisory Committee (RSTAC)Surveys and ProgramsObservatoryScience Planning ToolboxField of View OverlayPSF SimulationPandeiaSTIPSNews & EventsArticlesEventsPressDocumentationScience PublicationsTechnical DocumentationMikulski Archive for Space Telescopes (MAST)Scientific CommunityCommunity MissionsServicesPeer ReviewMissionsAdvanced ConceptsGrants AdministrationAbout GrantsFrequently Asked QuestionsNHFP Grant ResourcesSTScI Library and Institutional ArchiveOur CollectionsInstitutional ArchiveMissions PublicationsBibliography MethodologyOur CatalogSoftwareAstronomer's Proposal Tool (APT)LinuxMac OSXWindowsPrevious APT ReleasesHST Training MaterialsExposure Time CalculatorDrizzlePacFeaturesFrequently Asked QuestionsInstrument CharacteristicsaXeaXedrizzleScientific CareersSTScI ResearchResearch Topics and ProgramsRussell B. Makidon Optics LaboratoryMeet the TeamNews from the LabInstitute for Planets and LifeAstrophysicsPlanetary SciencesBiological SciencesEvents and LecturesRelated ResourcesExoplanet and Planetary ScienceHST Exoplanet and Planetary ScienceJWST Exoplanet and Planetary SciencePlanet Discovery and DemographicsPlanet CharacterizationSolar SystemPlanetary System Formation and EvolutionArchives and High Level Data ProductsSoftware and ToolsResearch DirectoryFellowshipsNASA Hubble Fellowship ProgramNHFP Host Institution Employment PolicyFrequently Asked QuestionsAnnouncement of OpportunityScience Categories and TechniquesFrequently Asked QuestionsAdvice for ApplicantsResources for Current FellowsVisa and Benefits Information2020 NHFP Fellows2019 NHFP Fellows2018 NHFP Fellows2017 and Prior FellowsAnnouncement of OpportunityGiacconi FellowshipPast FellowsLasker FellowshipPast FellowsExoplanet Science FellowshipPast FellowsSTScI Postdoctoral FellowshipPast FellowsDavidsen FellowshipPast FellowsCaroline Herschel Visitor ProgramPast VisitorsNews CenterJournalist ResourcesScientist ResourcesNews Release Submission FormNewslettersEventsWebcastsWebcast FAQsCommunications and OutreachNews ProductionSTEM LearningPublic OutreachPublic Lecture SeriesOpportunitiesHow to ApplyBenefitsOur WorkOur CultureDiversity, Inclusion, and EquityEmployee Resource GroupsTraining ProgramsCode of ConductCommunity ConnectionsMeet Our StaffSpace Astronomy Summer ProgramProgram DetailsApplication InformationHousing and TransportationWorking at the InstituteFrequently Asked QuestionsArchived Student PresentationsYouth for Astronomy & EngineeringContact UsLocal InformationGetting Here
Breadcrumbs Navigation
Home
(+)
Online Privacy Policy
Expand All
Collapse All
Information We Collect
In order to understand who uses our online resources and how they are used, when you visit the STScI website or use online applications, we collect basic information such as the date and time, internet protocol (IP) address, information about your web browser and computer (computer type, browser type), the resources you visit on our site, the amount of data transmitted, etc. We use this information to generate aggregate statistics on the usage of our site. We share this aggregate information with NASA and with our parent organization (AURA). Some of this aggregate information will be made available to the public. We will not use this information to identify or track usage by individuals, except as necessary to provide user support and maintain our systems. Non-aggregated information is only available to STScI and authorized contractors.
We do not sell, rent or exchange this information to anyone outside of STScI. We use this information only for the purpose of understanding how our resources are used and how they may be improved.
A "cookie" is a piece of data that our web site transfers to your web browser to allow it to remember specific information about your visit. Some STScI web pages use cookies. We may use both session and persistent cookies. Session cookies last only as long as your web browser is open. Persistent cookies store information on your computer for longer periods of time. We use cookies to allow better navigation on our pages and to allow you to customize preferences. If you do not wish to have session or persistent cookies stored on your computer, you may disable them in your browser. However, this may prevent some STScI services from functioning properly.
Information You Supply
Some of our web pages and online applications may ask for personal information such as your email address, postal address, or institutional information. We may also require you to create an account to use some of our resources. We use this information only to provide you with access to the specified service. We may share this information with NASA, ESA, AURA, and other astronomical institutions.
Information You Share
Some of our services (e.g. blogs, wikis) allow you to contribute information which will be seen by other users of those pages, or by the public. This information may be indexed by search engines such as Google or Bing. You should exercise discretion to not reveal personal information.
Monitoring
STScI monitors computer and network systems to ensure that our services are available to the intended users. We monitor the computer and network systems to identify attempts to deny service or make unauthorized changes. Anyone using our systems expressly consents to such monitoring and is advised that if monitoring reveals evidence of possible abuse or criminal activity, such evidence may be provided to law enforcement officials. If we see evidence of improper access, we may, without notice, remove access for some or all users in order to further investigate the situation. We will restore the service as quickly as possible and provide the community with information about the situation.
Email Subscriptions
STScI maintains lists of subscribers who have asked to receive email updates. A recipient may unsubscribe from future messages via a link at the bottom of each email message. We do not sell, rent, exchange, or otherwise disclose our subscriber lists to persons or organizations outside STScI.
Links to External Sites
To provide you with general information, our site contains links to external (non-STScI) sites. You should realize that such links are subject to the privacy and security policies of the external site and that the STScI Online Privacy Policy does not apply. We can't guarantee the accuracy or relevance of information on an external site. A link to an external site is not an endorsement by the STScI.
Social Websites
To better communicate with the public and astronomical community, STScI uses social websites such as Facebook, Twitter, and YouTube to disseminate information and to engage the community. STScI does not own, manage, or control the applications on social websites. Information that you supply to those sites is subject to their privacy and security policies and the STScI Online Privacy Policy does not apply.
Data Retention
The information we collect may be retained indefinitely.
Notification
In the event of a breach, or reasonable suspicion of a breach which allows an unauthorized person to access personally identifiable information, we will inform you as soon as possible. This notice may be sent to you individually, or we may notify you via STScI applications or our social media presence.
Accessibility Statement
We strive to ensure that our resources are accessible to individuals with disabilities in accordance with Section 508 of the Rehabilitation Act. If you have any difficulty viewing any page with adaptive technology, please contact us.
Disclosure
We will share any information we have, including personal information, with organizations or individuals outside of STScI if we have a good-faith belief that this is reasonably necessary to:
Meet applicable law, regulation, legal process, or enforceable governmental request.
Enforce applicable policies, including investigation of potential violations.
Detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues.
Protect against harm to the rights, property, or safety of STScI, our users or the public as required or permitted by law.
Children and Privacy
We believe in the importance of protecting the privacy of children online and do not knowingly contact or collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Our services are not intended to solicit information of any kind from children under 13. To notify us of our receipt of information from children under 13, please contact us.
Questions
If you have questions about this policy, or you have a privacy concern, please contact us.
Last reviewed: September 29, 2020
contact us
Close
Accessibility Questions
Name *
Email *
Message *
*Denotes a required field.
Submit
This site is protected by reCAPTCHA and the Google
Privacy Policy and Terms of Service apply.
Close
Submission in progress
Processing...
contact us
Close
Children and Privacy Questions
Name *
Email *
Message *
*Denotes a required field.
Submit
This site is protected by reCAPTCHA and the Google
Privacy Policy and Terms of Service apply.
Close
Submission in progress
Processing...
contact us
Close
Privacy Questions
Name *
Email *
Message *
*Denotes a required field.
Submit
This site is protected by reCAPTCHA and the Google
Privacy Policy and Terms of Service apply.
Close
Submission in progress
Processing...
Back to top
ApplyBack To TopBlack HolesCalendarCaratCheckbox CheckedCircle Arrow TriangleCircle ArrowCloseComputersConfidentialCosmologyDiningEssayExcel File IconExpand IconExpandExternal LinkFacebookFlickrGalaxiesGoogle PlusGroup HousingHamburgerHistorical ContextHousingHubble BlogHubble EbooksHubble Future Mission WebbHubble Future Mission WFIRSTHubble LearningHubble MilestonesHubble Telescope MissionHubble Telescope RoundHubble TimelineHubble VideoIconmonstr Google Plus 4IdeaImage File IconInstagramInvestigatorJohns Hopkins Planets LifeJWST ARJWST Telescope RoundKey ConceptsMenu Close BlueMenu Open BlueMinusPDF File IconPhoto IconPlanetsPlusPowerpoint File IconProfileprofile2Question Circle?ReferencesReleaseReplyRequirementsResumeRetweetReviewRocketRssSearchShareSlider Chevron PrevSlider ChevronSlider DashSolar SystemSpace Galaxy IconStellar PhysicsStellar PopulationsSTScI Icon LineSTScI Logo No TextSTScI Logo Planers LifeSTScI LogoText File IconTimelineTransportationTwitter LikeTwitterUniversityUploadVideo File IconVideo TriangleWFIRST Telescope RoundWord File IconWorldYoutubeZip File Icon
